speechcounts.org 2014-06-29

# Privacy Policy for Our Web Site

**see also:** Web Site Terms of Use and [ASHA Community Terms of Use](http://community.asha.org/ASHA/CommunityGuidelines)

This Privacy Statement discloses the privacy practices for the American Speech-Language-Hearing Association ("ASHA") and its Internet Web site: <http://www.asha.org/> (hereinafter referred to individually as a "Web site"). ASHA, an independent, non-profit organization, provides you with the following information:

  * What personally identifiable information of yours or third-party personal identification is collected from you through the Web site;
  * How the information is used;
  * With whom the information may be shared;
  * What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information;
  * What security procedures are in place to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of information under ASHA's control; and
  * How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

If you feel that ASHA is not abiding by its posted privacy policy, you should first contact the ASHA Action Center at 800-498-2071. 

**Information Collection and Use**

ASHA, or third parties designated by ASHA, collects personally identifiable and non-personally identifiable information from users in a variety of ways. ASHA is the sole owner of all the information collected on the Web site, and may use and share with third parties any and all of the information collected in any manner whatsoever that it deems appropriate for business purposes in its sole discretion. 

**Registration**

To access areas designated as "member areas," users must be current members or affiliates of ASHA. The information collected when members join ASHA is also used to control access to these areas of the Web site. ASHA members and affiliates who wish to use the "member areas" of the Web site will be required initially to enter certain personal identification information (e.g., current ASHA account number, last name, e-mail address, username and password) to gain access.

**Online Orders**

ASHA requests information from its users on its membership form, including contact information (such as name and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date, etc.). This information is primarily used by ASHA and third parties designated by ASHA for billing and to fill customer orders, but may be used by ASHA or third parties designated by ASHA for other business purposes. For example, if there is a problem processing an order, this information may be used to contact the user.

**Cookies**

Currently there are two types of cookies. The standard cookie is information about the user stored on the user's hard drive. The second type of cookie, called a session cookie, also stores information about a user. However, these cookies are not stored on the user's hard drive. These cookies are used only while the user is actively connected to a Web site. Once the user closes the Internet browser (or is inactive for more than 20 minutes), these session cookies are destroyed. ASHA uses both types of cookies on its Web site. In the future, ASHA may add additional cookies for business purposes. 

ASHA uses permanent cookies for several business purposes. Primarily, when visitors arrive at our site, a unique cookie is automatically stored on the visitor's computer by their Internet browser that allows analysis software to differentiate between new and returning users.

Second, a permanent cookie is written when members opt to save their log-on information. This cookie saves time for members because they do not have to enter security information for each visit to the site. If members reject the cookie, they may still use the Web site but they will have to manually log in to access "member areas." 

Finally, session cookies are used while a user is active on the Web site for a multitude of business purposes. For example, these cookies allow members to navigate freely through the Web site once they have logged in to the Web site. Without these cookies, members would have to login each time they requested a "member area" page. These cookies are also used while a member is joining, renewing or altering account information. This allows the Web site to track a user's activity before any data is committed to a database.

**Log Files**

Each view of a page on the Web site is logged. Information such as the user's Internet Protocol ("IP") address, time of day and duration of activity on the Web site is recorded. This information may be used by ASHA or third parties designated by ASHA to analyze trends, administer the Web site, track users' movements and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use or for other business purposes. 

If illegal activity is detected on the Web site, ASHA or third parties designated by ASHA may attempt to connect an IP address to personal information.

**Sharing**

ASHA will share aggregated demographic information with third parties, including without limitation its partners and advertisers, as it deems appropriate in its sole discretion. 

From time to time, we share personally identifiable information, as ASHA deems appropriate in its sole discretion, with third parties in a number of ways for a variety of business purposes, including name and other personally identifiable information.

**Links**

The Web site contains links to other Internet sites. Please be aware that ASHA is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other Internet sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave the Web site and to read the privacy statements of each Internet site that collects personally identifiable information. This Privacy Statement applies solely to information collected by ASHA's Web site.

**Surveys**

From time to time, ASHA, or third parties designated by ASHA, requests information from users via surveys. Information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address) and demographic information (such as zip code). Survey information may be used by ASHA, or third parties designated by ASHA, for a variety of business purposes. For example, surveys will be used for purposes of monitoring or improving the use of and satisfaction with the Web site and other services offered by ASHA.

**Security**

When you submit information via the Web site, ASHA, or third parties designated by ASHA, takes certain precautions to protect your user information both online and offline. For example, currently, when registration/order forms on our Web site ask users to enter information (such as credit card number and/or social security number), that information is encrypted and is protected with encryption software: Secure Sockets Layer ("SSL"). While you are on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on your Internet browser becomes locked, as opposed to unlocked or open. These security features may be updated from time-to-time in ASHA's sole discretion. 

Just as we currently use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also use certain efforts to protect user-information offline. Currently, our users' information is restricted primarily in our offices and our servers are all password protected. 

If you have any questions about the current state of security with respect to information collected at the Web site or stored offline, you may send an email to [webmaster@asha.org](mailto:webmaster@asha.org).

**Special Offers**

ASHA sends all new members a welcoming e-mail to verify password and username. Members and other visitors to our Web site may occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, newsletters and other information from ASHA, or third parties designated by ASHA. ASHA, or third parties designated by ASHA, may also send notifications of renewals and other communications to members via e-mail.

**Site and Service Updates**

ASHA also sends user site and service announcement updates. Members cannot opt-out from service announcements, which contain important information about the service. We communicate with users to provide requested services and in regard to issues relating to their account via e-mail or phone.

**Correcting/Updating Personal Information**

If a user's personally identifiable information (such as zip code) changes or if a user no longer desires our service, we will endeavor to provide a way to correct or update personal data which that user has provided to us. This can usually be done from our member center page or by contacting our Action Center at 800-498-2071. Some information, such as a user's name change, must be changed by calling the Action Center at 800-498-2071.

**Choice/Opt-out**

Users who no longer wish to receive our e-mail newsletters or promotional materials may opt-out of receiving a specific communication from ASHA by sending a reply e-mail containing the word "unsubscribe" in the subject line. Please note that there are certain communications which will still be sent to users by ASHA, or third parties designated by ASHA, as referenced above, including without limitation site and Service Updates and membership renewals.

**Notification of Changes**

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on ASHA's homepage so that our users are always informed of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.
